Daniel Obed

4 years working experience in manufacturing as analyst in PPIC

Portfolio

January 2023

About Me

I am a responsible, professional, and detail person with four years of experience in Manufacturing and Industrial as PPIC. I also proficient in SQL, Python, Tableau, and Excel/Spreadsheet. I'm strong critical thinking, problem solver, and continuous improvement. With the skills and experiences mentioned, I believe I can become a great data analyst in your company.









Education



RevoU (2022 - 2023)

Full Stack Data Analyst (Certificate)

(Final Project)



Maranatha Christian University (2014 - 2018)

Bachelor Degree Industrial Engineering

GPA: 3.28

Skills & Abilities



SQL (Link)



Python (Link)



Excel (Link)



Tableau (Link)

Soft Skills:

- Leadership
- Analytical Skills
- Critical Thinking
- Team Work

- Problem Solving
- Continuous Improvement
- Adaptability

Experience



Group Leader PPIC (2019 - present)

PT Prokemas Adhikari Kreasi

- Make daily month to date and bi-weekly reports to supervisor.
- Analyze and make improvements to reduce the waste produced by the raw material plan.
- Forecasting raw material requirement for the next month
- Monitoring stock availability of supplier raw materials and delivery schedules based on production plans.
- Monitoring plan of raw materials for production in the most efficient way.
- Continuous improvement of the system in PPIC.

Skills : Analytics Skill, Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Forecasting, Leadership, Communication, Excel. Achievement : Monthly lower grade usage up to 80%.

Production Planning and Inventory Control Staff (2018 - 2019) PT Prokemas Adhikari Kreasi

- Make daily reports of raw materials waste and stock on hand to supervisor.
- Forecasting raw materials requirements for next month.
- Planning raw materials for production with the most efficient waste.
- Scheduling delivery of raw materials based on production plans.
- Controlling the raw material stock level.
- Make purchase request of raw materials based on raw materials forecast and supplier's production plan.

Skills: Analytics Skill, Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Forecasting, Inventory Management, Excel/Spreadshee Achievement: Monthly waste produced 1.13% (Target was 1.4%).

Teacher Bimbel Global

Middle School Mathematics and Physics Teacher for 6 years.

Avg Student : 6-8 students

List of Projects (from Labs)

Detail of Projects (from Labs)